

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER 136 Belvedere Street, San Francisco jacob.sf.us@gmail.com (415) 766-1867 https://linkedin.com/in/jacobswartz

In-depth understanding of software development fundamentals. Specialized experience in eCommerce and SEO & SEM. Intuition for detail and visual aesthetics. Highly self-motivated – capable of working independently as well as being a key asset to any team, with a passion to share knowledge and improve & expand skillsets.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

#### Development

- Object-oriented PHP
- JavaScript
- Bash
- Node.js/Vue.js/Webpack
- HTM5L/CSS3/Sass
- SVN/git
- MySQL
- Apache
- xcache/memcache
- SEO/SEM

#### Testing

- PHPUnit/xdebug
- JMeter/Apache Bench
- KCachegrind
- New Relic/Yslow/PageSpeed

# Collaboration

- IRC
- Basecamp
- Trac
- JIRA

#### Virtualization

- VirtualBox/VMWare
- Vagrant/PuPHPet
- Amazon Web Services
- Docker

## OS

- Debian Linux
- MacOS
- · Windows 7, 10

# **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Freelance Consultant**

#### The Internet; Jan 2015 - Present

- · Develop, maintain, and manage sites and custom features for clients
- Install and configure versioning, web, and mailservers
- · Utilize APIs to quickly import product metadata, reducing ingestion time
- Generate tailored reports from cart platforms for e-commerce clients
- Create email campaigns using MailChimp and Campaign Monitor

# Lead Creative Consultant at Bluestone Creative Cincinnati, Ohio; Mar 2014 - Sep 2014

- Implemented and configured hardware for in-house web, storage, and FTP servers
- Set up tools for project tracking, task management, and time logging
- Created website boilerplates for various categories of clients

# Software Engineer at Ask.com

#### Cincinnati, Ohio: Mar 2014 - Sep 2014

- Worked on an agile development team responsible for 3+ million unique articles and Q&A pairs
- Repaired sites affected by Google's search algorithm "Panda", resuming AdSense revenue
- Led team to use more efficient processes in order to more rapidly create, edit, and share mockups and one-offs
- Migrated top revenue earning sites to dotCMS under strict deadlines

Continued on next page...



SOFTWARE DEVELOPER SOFTWARE DEVELOPER
136 Belvedere Street, San Francisco
jacob.sf.us@gmail.com (415) 766-1867 https://linkedin.com/in/jacobswartz

## **EXPERIENCE CONT'D**

# Web Developer at FontShop International, Inc San Francisco, California; Oct 2008 – July 2012

- Created a dynamic, responsive eCommerce experience using HTML5, CSS3 + Sass, and JavaScript
- Optimized pages to decrease load time and increase SEO ranking
- Developed font rendering tool for sampling over 100,000 typefaces
- Implemented sitewide templating and internationalization supporting 4 languages
- Migrated from cumbersome images and Flash hacks to webfonts with TypeKit
- · Worked with payment processing systems: CyberSource, Ogone
- Maintained WordPress blog extended with custom features
- Helped organize and run TYPO one of Europe's most successful design conferences for its U.S. premiere at Yerba Buena Center for the Arts

# Web Developer at Fish Flirt Marketing Dayton, Ohio; May 2007 - Oct 2008

- Developed and maintained websites for clients using the LAMP stack. W3C compliant HTML4, CSS2, and JavaScript
- Installed, configured, and managed SVN, web, and mail servers

**EDUCATION** 

Sinclair Community College Dayton, Ohio; Apr 2007 - Oct 2008 • AAS, Computer Information Systems

REFERENCES Available on request